<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts | Academic</title>
    <link>https://example.com/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Posts</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lightweight markup languages.</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/markup_languages/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/markup_languages/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is a &amp;ldquo;markup language&amp;rdquo;?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A markup language is a set of codes that, when applied to plain text, allows you to add one or more of the following properties (among others):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Define the text&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Structure the text&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Describe the layout of the text&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Decorate the text&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One markup language you encounter every day (unless you&amp;rsquo;re a hermit) is hypertext markup language, or HTML. Websites and apps that bring you news and show you your email are built, at least in part, with HTML markup using tags as a mechanism for markup of raw text content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem with some markup languages (among them HTML) is that entering these tags manually is a very tedious task. And with other languages, such as XML, tags and their attributes make up more of the overall content than the text itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;examples-of-markup-languages&#34;&gt;Examples of markup languages&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Markup languages are used wherever it is required to obtain formatted text based on text alone: in typography (SGML, TeX, PostScript, RTF), computer user interfaces (Microsoft Word, OpenOffice), the World Wide Web (HTML, XHTML, XML, WML, VML, PGML, SVG, XBRL).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;lightweight-markup-languages&#34;&gt;Lightweight markup languages&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you wanted to take advantage of markup languages, for example by publishing an HTML page on the internet or converting a DocBook file to PDF so that it could be printed, you had to do one of two things. On the one hand, you can spend time learning these languages from the inside and outside, writing them down manually, and then checking your work three times. Or you could invest the money in a tool that manages the complexity of them for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, some enterprising developers have come up with a third option. They created new markup languages that contained many (in some cases most or all) of the functions of heavier analogues, but greatly simplified the syntax.
They are used where a person has to prepare text in a regular text editor (blogs, forums, wikis), or where it is important that a user with a regular text editor can also read the text. Here are some widely used lightweight markup languages:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BBCode&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Markdown&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;reStructuredText&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Textile&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wiki markup&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Various auto-documentation systems (for example, Javadoc).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;html&#34;&gt;HTML&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most common language is HTML (an abbreviation of the English Hypertext Markup Language − &amp;ldquo;hypertext markup language&amp;rdquo;). It is standard for Internet documents, with its help all web pages are created. Documents that contain a special code are processed by browsers and presented to users in a convenient interface. Thus, you get the opportunity to view pages, print them, use them to transfer data to servers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;textile&#34;&gt;Textile&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is one of the simplest markup languages, has somewhat more functionality. Its main task is to automatically convert text into markup while maintaining the breakdown into paragraphs. The language is used in CMS Textpattern.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;bbcode&#34;&gt;BBCode&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The abbreviation from the English Bulletin Board Code is a markup language that is used for formatting (formatting) messages on various electronic bulletin boards, forums, comments, personal messages, and so on. Tags similar to HTML tags are used to format the text. Unlike HTML tags, BBCode is enclosed in square brackets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;latex&#34;&gt;LaTeX&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a markup language that is capable of automating many operations related to the layout of documents, such as automatic page numbering, creation of tables, illustrations, formulas, cross-references, headers, footers, subject indexes, tables of contents and references. Being distributed under the LaTeX Project Public License, LaTeX refers to free software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;markdown&#34;&gt;Markdown&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Markdown is an easy way to add formatting. — for example, headings, bold/italic text and lists — in plain text. Instead of relying on HTML or WYSIWYG editors, Markdown allows you to create full pages of formatted text without having to take your fingers off the keyboard, and it&amp;rsquo;s all much more intuitive than HTML.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the idea of using markup languages with text documents was developing, this increased the use of markup languages in other areas, they suggested using them to represent various types of information, including playlists, vector graphics, web services, user interfaces.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My last week</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/my_last_week/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/my_last_week/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;get-started&#34;&gt;Get Started&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My last week flew by unnoticed. For almost the whole week, I was dealing with Operating systems and a Computer workshop on IT. Over the past week, I have completed two laboratory works and the stage 1st of an Individual project on Operating systems, as well as laboratory work on a Computer workshop on IT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That week was fun, because during the installation of the second operating system (Linux) on my laptop, Windows was accidentally demolished. The only thing that calmed me was that there were no particularly important documents, since I reinstalled it before starting my studies. Because of this oversight, I had to reinstall everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I said earlier, I completed laboratory work №3 and №4, the 1st stage of an Individual project on OS. In the process of doing laboratory work №3, I learned how to make reports using the lightweight Markdown markup language. It was necessary to make a report in Markdown format on laboratory work №2, it turned out not to be very difficult. And as a result of laboratory work №4, I learned how to work in the Terminal, acquired practical skills of user interaction with the system via the command line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was also interesting to do laboratory work on a Computer workshop on IT. There I study the Arduino programming language. Throughout the module, we will perform laboratory work on robotics using an Arduino microcontroller.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In general, my last week was quite productive and entertaining.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My last week 2</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/my_last_week-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/my_last_week-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-was-my-second-week&#34;&gt;How was my second week?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week, in honor of the holiday, we had one day off. On this day, my friends and I took a walk around Moscow. The rest of my days were also devoted to Laboratory work on OS, programming technology and a Computer workshop on IT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the OS, we did the 2nd stage of the project and two laboratory works №5 and №6. In Laboratory work №5, I got acquainted with the Linux file system, its structure, names and contents of directories. In addition, I acquired practical skills in using commands to work with files and directories, managing processes (and works), checking disk usage and maintaining the file system. And in Laboratory work №6, I got acquainted with the tools for searching files and filtering text data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And also acquired practical skills: process management (and tasks), disk usage verification and file system maintenance. In the 2nd stage of the project, it was necessary to fill out information about yourself on the website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still practice programming technology in C++, and at the computer workshop on IT - in Arduino. In general, the whole subsequent module will be full of programming for me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Version control.Git.</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/git/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/git/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In recent years, the popularity of git has shown explosive growth. This version control system is used by various open source projects. You can start by learning the most commonly used commands, and then gradually expand your knowledge. This is exactly what we will do in this article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-git&#34;&gt;What is Git?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GIT is a distributed version control system created by Linus Torvalds to manage the development of the Linux kernel and is currently very widespread among software developers. Git has two main tasks: the first is to store information about all changes in your code, starting from the very first line, and the second is to ensure the convenience of teamwork on the code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-a-version-control-system&#34;&gt;What is a Version Control System?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Version Control System (VCS)&lt;/strong&gt; is a software to facilitate working with changing information. The version control system allows you to store multiple versions of the same document, go back to earlier versions if necessary, determine who made a change and when, and much more. Such systems are most widely used in software development for storing the source codes of the program being developed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Version control software keeps track of all changes made to the code in a special database. If an error is detected, developers can go back and perform a comparison with earlier versions of the code to fix errors, minimizing problems for all team members.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;centralized-version-control-systems&#34;&gt;Centralized version control systems&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Centralized version control systems&lt;/strong&gt; are client-server applications, when the project repository exists in a single instance and is stored on the server. Access to it was carried out through a special client application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CVS (Concurrent Versions System, Simultaneous Versions System)&lt;/strong&gt; is one of the first systems that became widespread among developers, it originated in the late 80s of the last century. Currently, this product is not being developed, this is primarily due to a number of key drawbacks, such as the inability to rename files, inefficient storage, and almost complete lack of integrity control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Subversion&lt;/strong&gt; (SVN) is a version control system created to replace CVS. SVN was developed in 2004 and is still in use. Despite many advantages over CVS, SVN still has disadvantages, such as problems with renaming, inability to delete data from storage, problems in the branch merge operation, etc. In general, SVN was (and remains) a significant step forward compared to CVS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;distributed-version-control-systems&#34;&gt;Distributed version control systems&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Distributed Version Control Systems&lt;/strong&gt; (DVCS) allow you to store a repository (a copy of it) for each developer working with this system. At the same time, it is possible to allocate a central repository (conditionally) to which changes from local ones will be sent and, with it, these local repositories will be synchronized. When working with such a system, users periodically synchronize their local repositories with the central one and work directly with their local copy. After making a sufficient number of changes to the local copy, they (changes) are sent to the server. At the same time, the server is most often chosen conditionally, since in most DVCS there is no such thing as a “dedicated server with a central repository&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;git-hosting&#34;&gt;Git hosting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A number of services provide hosting for git repositories, among the most famous are GitHub, Codebase, SourceForge, SourceHut, Gitea, Bitbucket, GitLab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-an-ssh-key-and-why-is-it-needed&#34;&gt;What is an SSH key and why is it needed?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To work from your computer with GitHub, to have access to projects stored on the service, to execute commands in the console without constantly confirming the password, you need to log in with the server. SSH keys help with this.
Each SSH key contains a pair: a public (public) and a private (private) key. The public key is sent to the server, you don&amp;rsquo;t have to hide it from everyone and not worry that someone will see it and steal it. It is useless without its private key pair. But the private key is the secret part. Only you should have access to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;basic-git-commands&#34;&gt;Basic git commands&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;git add&lt;/strong&gt; command adds the contents of the working directory to the index (staging area) for a subsequent commit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;git status&lt;/strong&gt; command shows the status of files in the working directory and index: which files have been modified but not added to the index; which are waiting for a commit in the index.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;git diff&lt;/strong&gt; command is used to calculate the difference between any two Git trees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;git commit&lt;/strong&gt; command takes all the data added to the index using git add and stores their cast in the internal database, and then shifts the pointer of the current branch to this cast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;git rm&lt;/strong&gt; command is used in Git to delete files from the index and working copy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;git mv&lt;/strong&gt; command is just a convenient way to move a file and then execute git add for the new file and git rm for the old one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;git clean&lt;/strong&gt; command is used to remove garbage from the working directory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have analyzed the basic knowledge of what a Version Control System and Git are. I tried to collect all the most important information and present it as succinctly and concisely as possible. Git is quite complex, and there are many more functions in it&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to Wowchemy, the website builder for Hugo</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Wowchemy website builder for Hugo, along with its starter templates, is designed for professional creators, educators, and teams/organizations - although it can be used to create any kind of site&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The template can be modified and customised to suit your needs. It&amp;rsquo;s a good platform for anyone looking to take control of their data and online identity whilst having the convenience to start off with a &lt;strong&gt;no-code solution (write in Markdown and customize with YAML parameters)&lt;/strong&gt; and having &lt;strong&gt;flexibility to later add even deeper personalization with HTML and CSS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can work with all your favourite tools and apps with hundreds of plugins and integrations to speed up your workflows, interact with your readers, and much more&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-the-template-is-mobile-first-with-a-responsive-design-to-ensure-that-your-site-looks-stunning-on-every-device&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/wowchemy/wowchemy-hugo-modules/master/academic.png&#34; alt=&#34;The template is mobile first with a responsive design to ensure that your site looks stunning on every device.&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      The template is mobile first with a responsive design to ensure that your site looks stunning on every device.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;get-started&#34;&gt;Get Started&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;👉 &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/templates/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create a new site&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;📚 &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Personalize your site&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;💬 &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/z8wNYzb&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Chat with the &lt;strong&gt;Wowchemy community&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://discourse.gohugo.io&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hugo community&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🐦 Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/wowchemy&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;@wowchemy&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/GeorgeCushen&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;@GeorgeCushen&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/search?q=%23MadeWithWowchemy&amp;amp;src=typed_query&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;#MadeWithWowchemy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;💡 &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/wowchemy/wowchemy-hugo-modules/issues&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Request a &lt;strong&gt;feature&lt;/strong&gt; or report a &lt;strong&gt;bug&lt;/strong&gt; for &lt;em&gt;Wowchemy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;⬆️ &lt;strong&gt;Updating Wowchemy?&lt;/strong&gt; View the &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/hugo-tutorials/update/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Update Tutorial&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/updates/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Release Notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;crowd-funded-open-source-software&#34;&gt;Crowd-funded open-source software&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To help us develop this template and software sustainably under the MIT license, we ask all individuals and businesses that use it to help support its ongoing maintenance and development via sponsorship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-click-here-to-become-a-sponsor-and-help-support-wowchemys-future-httpswowchemycomplans&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/plans/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;❤️ Click here to become a sponsor and help support Wowchemy&amp;rsquo;s future ❤️&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a token of appreciation for sponsoring, you can &lt;strong&gt;unlock &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/plans/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;these&lt;/a&gt; awesome rewards and extra features 🦄✨&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ecosystem&#34;&gt;Ecosystem&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/wowchemy/hugo-academic-cli&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Hugo Academic CLI&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; Automatically import publications from BibTeX&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;inspiration&#34;&gt;Inspiration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://academic-demo.netlify.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Check out the latest &lt;strong&gt;demo&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of what you&amp;rsquo;ll get in less than 10 minutes, or &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/user-stories/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;view the &lt;strong&gt;showcase&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of personal, project, and business sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;features&#34;&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Page builder&lt;/strong&gt; - Create &lt;em&gt;anything&lt;/em&gt; with &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/page-builder/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;widgets&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/content/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;elements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edit any type of content&lt;/strong&gt; - Blog posts, publications, talks, slides, projects, and more!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create content&lt;/strong&gt; in &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/content/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Markdown&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/import/jupyter/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jupyter&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/install-locally/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RStudio&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Plugin System&lt;/strong&gt; - Fully customizable &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/customization/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;color&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;font themes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Display Code and Math&lt;/strong&gt; - Code highlighting and &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikibooks.org/wiki/LaTeX/Mathematics&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;LaTeX math&lt;/a&gt; supported&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Integrations&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://analytics.google.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Google Analytics&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://disqus.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Disqus commenting&lt;/a&gt;, Maps, Contact Forms, and more!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Beautiful Site&lt;/strong&gt; - Simple and refreshing one page design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Industry-Leading SEO&lt;/strong&gt; - Help get your website found on search engines and social media&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Media Galleries&lt;/strong&gt; - Display your images and videos with captions in a customizable gallery&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mobile Friendly&lt;/strong&gt; - Look amazing on every screen with a mobile friendly version of your site&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multi-language&lt;/strong&gt; - 34+ language packs including English, 中文, and Português&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multi-user&lt;/strong&gt; - Each author gets their own profile page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Privacy Pack&lt;/strong&gt; - Assists with GDPR&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stand Out&lt;/strong&gt; - Bring your site to life with animation, parallax backgrounds, and scroll effects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One-Click Deployment&lt;/strong&gt; - No servers. No databases. Only files.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;themes&#34;&gt;Themes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wowchemy and its templates come with &lt;strong&gt;automatic day (light) and night (dark) mode&lt;/strong&gt; built-in. Alternatively, visitors can choose their preferred mode - click the moon icon in the top right of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://academic-demo.netlify.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Demo&lt;/a&gt; to see it in action! Day/night mode can also be disabled by the site admin in &lt;code&gt;params.toml&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/customization&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Choose a stunning &lt;strong&gt;theme&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;font&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for your site. Themes are fully customizable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;license&#34;&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Copyright 2016-present &lt;a href=&#34;https://georgecushen.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;George Cushen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Released under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/wowchemy/wowchemy-hugo-modules/blob/master/LICENSE.md&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;MIT&lt;/a&gt; license.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
